Guide to the Brooklyn letterhead collection BCMS.0008
Brooklyn Collection
- Thompson, Edward, 1881
  Sanitary engineer and plumber. 86 Atlantic Ave.
- Thompson, James, 1878
  Grocer. 121 Atlantic Street
- Thompson, Job. C. / Thompson's, 1875
  Hat and fur store. 595 Fulton St., opp. Flatbush Ave.
- Thompson, Samuel's Nephew, 1868-1869
  Coal and wood dealer. Foot Columbia Street
- Thompson, W.A., 1879
  Mason and builder. 357 Clinton St.
- Thomson Meter Co., 1892, 1901, 1904
  Water meter maker. 39 to 43 York St. and 79 to 83 Washington St.
- Thorn, A.B., 1884-1885
  Fire insurance agent. 202, 203 Montague Street
- Thorne, T.G., 1888
  Rubber goods. 211 Fulton Street
- Thorne, Theo. A., 1887
  Real estate. 944 Fulton Street
- Thornton, Edward, 1874, 1886
  Hardware dealer. 1045, 1046 Fulton Street
- Thrift, The, 1931, 1941
  Bank. Founded by Charles Pratt 1889. 255 Ryerson Street; DeKalb Ave. and Ryerson St.
- Thurston & Mesick, 1868
  Painters' supplies. 67 Broadway (formerly S. 7th, cor. 3rd)
- Thurston, R.'s Sons, 1880-1882, 1888, 1892
  Painters' supplies, painters, decorators and paper hangers. 77 Broadway, cor. 3rd; 85 Broadway, cor. Berry St.
- Tice, Chas. B., 1902
  Painter and decorator. 704 Lafayette Avenue
- Tiebout, C.H. & Sons, 1890
  Hardware dealer. 31 Grand St. and 243-247 Kent Avenue
- Tierney, Patrick, 1898
  Horseshoer. 166 Carlton Avenue, near Myrtle Ave.
- Tilden, Joseph M., 1899
  Teacher. Erasmus Hall, Flatbush
- Tilly, Alfred, 1883, 1888, 1890
  Painter and decorator. 1395 Atlantic Ave.
- Tilly, H., 1878
  Carpenter and builder. Cor. Nostrand and Atlantic Avenues
- Tilly & Van Hagen Co., 1893
  Builders' hardware. 879 and 881 Gates Avenue
- Timmerman, H. & Son, 1906
  Produce dealer. 447 & 449 Harman Street
- Timmes, Peter's Son, 1898
  Iron work. 281-285 N. 6th and 306-310 N. 7th Sts.
- Tisch, Charles, Inc., 1937
  Appliances and roofing. 93-97 Rockwell Place
- Title Guarantee & Trust Company, 1897, 1932
  Real estate. 175 Remsen St. (removed from 26 Court St.) and 196 Montague Street
- Titus, George H., 1879, 1880, 1885
  Carpets etc. dealer. 607-611 Fulton St., opp. Flatbush Ave.
- Tompkins & Tuthill, 1895, 1902
  Paper dealers. 15, 92 Fulton Street
- Tonjes, Moller & Co., 1883
  Millers. 31-35 Broadway
- Tony the Old Reliable, 1928
  Produce dealer. Formerly of The Red Wagon. 1809 Centre Street near Seneca Ave., Ridegwood
- Toohill, Edward, 1867, 1876
  Plumber. 34 Hamilton Avenue; 156 Union Street, cor. Hicks
- Tooker, Wm. F., 1868
  Coach and carriage maker. 157 Fulton and 19 DeKalb Aves.
- Toole, John L., 1897
  Carpet cleaning. 150 2nd Ave. bet. 12th and 13th
- Totten, G.I., 1907
  Coal and wood dealer. 594 Kent Avenue
- Tracy & Heslin, 1885, 1887, 1890
  Plumbers. 405, 861 Bedford Avenue, near Myrtle
- Tracy, Thomas, 1879
  Sexton and undertaker. 178 Graham Street, near Myrtle Avenue
- Trainor, John, 1898
  Harness maker. 90 Boerum Place
- Travis, E.E., 1871
  Shoe dealer. 236 Court Street
- Treacy, James A., 1899
  Plumbing. 56 Court Street
- Treasury Department, 1873
  Washington D.C.
- Treber, Christopher (& Son, Inc.), 1915, 1935
  Undertaker and embalmer, 118 and 120 Greenpoint Avenue; Morticians, 102 Norman Avenue
- Tremaine, M.A., 1872
  Milliner. 285 Fulton St.
- Triboro Agency, Inc., Agents, 1942
  Insurance. 151 Montague Street
- Tripler, Edward L., 1884, 1894
  Mens' and boys' furnishing goods. 405-407 Fulton Street
- Trippel, Alex, 1869
  Liquor store. 18 Exchange Place
- Trommer, John F., Inc., 1940
  Restaurants and banquet rooms. 1632 Bushwick Avenue
- Trotzky, L., 1925
  Insurance and real estate. 497 Pennsylvania Avenue
- Trow Directory, Printing and Bookbinding Company, 1912
  Printing and publishing. 202 East 12th Street
- Trundy & Murphy, 1890
  Dock. Gowanus Canal, cor. Smith and Halleck Sts.
- Tulin, M., 1883
  Cabinet maker. 644 Atlantic Avenue
- Tunison, W.H., 1877, 1881
  Carpenter and builder. 273 Greene Avenue, near Classon
- Turoff, M. & Son, 1944
  Hardware and house furnishing. 2809 Mermaid Avenue
- Tuttle, S., Son & Co., 1872, 1879, 1880
  Coal and wood dealer. 40 Broadway; Several yard locations listed
- Tutty, James, 1891
  Horseshoer. Sandford Street, near Myrtle Avenue
- Tutty, John, 1899
  Horseshoer. 938 DeKalb Avenue
- Tyler, Frank H., 1894, 1916
  Real estate. 1183 Fulton Street
- U.S. Neon Signs, 1938
  Neon signs dealer. 674-676 Pacific Street
- Ullrich Bros., 1891
  Painters. 110 Moore St., cor. Humboldt St., and 167 Gwinnett St.
- Ulmer, Wm. Brewery, 1922
  31 Belvidere Street
- Underhill Society of America, 1920
  Family association. 248 Maple Street (Flatbush)
- Underwood, John & Co., 1894
  Chemists. Laboratory: 143-149 Grand Avenue
- Union House Repairing Co., The, 1912, 1914
  Plumbing. 747 Union Street near 5th Ave.
- Union Publishing Co., 1880
  Newspaper. Corner of Fulton and Front Streets
- Union Sawing and Planing Mill, 1890, 1896, 1899
  Woodworking. Cor. 8th St. and 2nd Ave.
- Union Steam Carpet Cleaning Co., The, 1884
  Carpet cleaning. 104 and 106 S. 8th Street
- United Nations Delegation of Agudat Israel
  United Nations delegation. 860 Pond Lane Woodmere NY
- United States Foundry Co, 1890
  Foundry. Leonard and Richardson Sts.
- United States Maritime Service
  Military. United States Maritime Training Station, Sheepshead Bay
- United States Motors, Inc., 1959
  Volkswagon dealer. 2501 Flatbush Avenue
- United States Navy Yard, 1941
  Military. Navy Yard, Brooklyn
- Uptegrove, Wm. E. & Bro., 1905
  Wood dealer. Foot Java St., East River
- Uptown Weekly, The, 1893
  Newspaper. 259 Marion Street
- Utowana Dancing Class, 1893
  Dance class. 14 Cambridge Place
- Vagt, R., 1914
  Food products factory. 35-41 Emerson Place
- Vail, E.G., 1878
  Carpenter and builder. 7 Bergen St., near Court
- Valentine, Bergen & Co., 1871, 1894
  Wholesale grocers. 15 Fulton Street
- Van Anden, I., 1860, 1864, 1865, 1869
  Printer. Office of the Brooklyn Daily Eagle. Eagle buildings, 30 & 32 Fulton St.
- Van Anden, W.M., 1870
  Notray public.
- Van Delft, John, 1875-1876
  Painter. Smith Street, near 9th; 455 Court Street
- Vanderbilt, E., 1881
- Vanderbilt, J., 1879
  Shoe dealer. 78 Court Street
- Vanderbilt, Oliver, 1859
- Vanderbilt, W.H. & J.W., 1898
  Coal dealer. 32 & 34 Rockwell Place
- Van Winkle, J.H., 1882
  Metal worker. 202 Division Avenue
- Van Wyck & Mykrantz Bros., 1892
  Wine and liquor dealers. 1248 Fulton Street
- Van Wynen, A. / Van Wynen & Son, 1865, 1878
  Carpenter and builder. 122 Harrison Street, near Hicks; 469 Hicks Street, near Harrison
- Varsity House Inc., 1960-1961
  School supplies. 383 Pearl Street
- Vaughan, Leonard N., 1916
  Real estate. 909 Fulton Street, cor. Clinton Ave.
- Veit, Fred, 1894
  Painter and decorator. 140 Huntington St.
- Veit, L.A., Miss, 1881
  Milliner. 310 Myrtle Avenue
- Ventrice, 1937
  Locksmith and repairs. 1799 Flatbush Avenue
- Verity, Elbert, 1878, 1880
  Lumber dealer. 93 Plymouth Street
- Vill & Corbett, 1901
  Painters and paper hangers. 106 Norman Ave., near leonard
- Vim, 1930
  Radios and parts. Concord and Liberty Sts.
- Vincent, L.H., 1887
  1709 Fulton St. and 729 Gates Avenue
- Vincent, Wm.
  Druggist. 139 Broadway
- Vineburg Store, The
  Dry goods and men's clothing. 442 Rogers Avenue
- Vining & Powell, 1862
  Metal worker. 104 Fulton Street
- Virginia Dare Extract Company, Inc., 1936
  Flavoring extract maker. Bush Terminal Building No. 10
- Voelkel & Apel, 1891
  Vehicle maker. 467 Flushing Avenue, near Bedford Ave.
- Vogel, Wm. & Bros. Tinware, 1889
  Tinware. 37-47 S. 9th St.
- Vogt, Henry & Bros. Man'f'g Co., 1896-1897
  Boiler makers. Works, 61-67 N. 13th Street; Office, 9 Kent Ave.
- Vogt, Henry A. & Sons, Inc., 1933
  Electrical contractors. 307 Broadway
- Voigt, Anthony, 1906
  Metal work. 396 Keap Street cor. S. 1st
- Voit Brothers, 1893
  Furniture makers. 36 Devoe Street
- Volkommer, Bloomingdale, & Co., 1893
  Hay and produce. Warehouse, foot 25th St.; Office, Palmer's Dock, Kent Ave. and N. 9th St.
- Vollkommer, Joseph, 1872
  Straw, feed and grain dealer. Junction of Broadway, Johnson and Union Aves.
- Vollmer, H., 1895
  Monument maker. 430 Jamaica Avenue
- Volz, Louis, 1906
  Carpenter and builder. 99 Evergreen Avenue
- Vom Lehn, Richard Sons, 1911
  Architects and contractors. 1565 New York Avenue
- Von Glahn Brothers / Henry Von Glahn & Son, 1897, 1906, 1909
  Wholesale grocers. Cor. Washington and Park Ave. (Wallabout)
- Vosburgh, W.C. Mfg. Co., 1888
  Gas fixture makers. 418 and 420 Fulton St.
- Vredenburgh, W.A., 1883
  Wooden ware and tables. 225 & 227 State Street, cor. Boerum
- Vreeland, S.B., 1867
  Architect and builder. Cor. Cranberry and Henry Sts, and 231 Court St.
- Vroman, S. & Co, 1901
  Hay and produce. Pier 2, Wallabout
- Vunck, W.L., 1901
  Mason and builder. Bay 19th St., near Benson Ave.
- Wachter & Herrmann, 1871
  Cabinet makers and upholsterers. 288 Court Street bet. Union and President Sts.
- Waechtler, John, 1866
  Night scavenger. 74 Throop Avenue and 347 Fulton St.
- Wagner, E.F., 1917
  Designer, American Studio. Photography and design. 229 Ovington Avenue
- Wagner, Joseph, 1900
  Carpenter and builder. 84 Debevoise Street
- Wagner, Ph., 1876
  Boot and shoe maker. 468 Court Street
- Waldhauer-Stevens Company, 1940
  Roofing and waterproofing. 1721-1725 Nostrand Avenue
- Waldron, A.J., 1925
  Real estate. 1153 Bedford Avenue
- Walgrain, Chas. O., 1881
  Mason and plasterer. 292 S. 3rd St.
- Walker, John, 1879
  Florist. 213 and 215 25th Street
- Wallabout Oil Works, 1879
  S. Jenney & Son. Oil dealer. Kent Avenue, foot of Rush Street
- Wallabout Presbyterian Church, Trustees of the, 1867
- Wallace Co., John W., 1903
  Sheet metal goods. 396-400 S. 2nd St.
- Wallberg, William F., 1879
  Painter and decorator. 627 Vanderbilt Avenue, near St. Marks
- Wallis, Wm., 1864, 1868
  Tin ware and metal roofer. 7 Prospect Street
- Wallman, Raimund, 1890
  Vehicle maker. 804 to 812 Flushing Ave., 31 to 35 Fayette St., bet. Broadway and Beaver
- Walsh, A.R., Prof., 1881
  Pianist. 179 Raymond St.
- Walsh, James, 1891
  Mason and plasterer. Corner DeKalb and Hudson Aves.
- Walsh, P., 1877
  74 Amity Street
- Walsh, R., 1894
  Horseshoer. Cor. 5th Ave. and 5th St.
- Walsh, Thomas C., 1867
  Magazine and newspaper vendor. 46 2nd Street
- Walters, Tobias, 1865
  Coach and carriage maker. Cor. Henry and Poplar Sts.
- Wamsley, Joseph H., 1873
  Union Place Plumbing, Steam & Gas Fitting Establishment. 138 Union Place (Union Avenue), bet. Clay and Dupont Sts.
- Wandelt, Samuel, 1887
  Cooper. 61-65 N. 3rd St., bet. 1st and 2nd Sts.
- Ward Baking Co., 1916
  Bakery. 802 Pacific Street
- Ward, Daniel, 1899-1900
  Horseshoer. Corner 28th Street and Third Avenue
- Ward, James, 1862
  Dry goods. 330 Grand Street
- Ward, John, 1864
  Cemetery railing painter.
- Ward, John, 1867, 1877
  Grocer. 683, 688 Myrtle Avenue; 727 Fulton Street
- Warmers, Louis, 1899
  Case Maker. 63 Scholes Street
- Warner, Gordon L., 1898
  Printer and bookseller. 154 Atlantic Avenue
- Warwick Valley Milk & Cream Co., 1890
  Dairy. 44-48 Boerum Place
- Wasel, Christian, 1897
  Coppersmith. 50 & 52 N. 3rd St.
- Washington Ice Company, 1869
  Ice distributor. 393 and 395 Canal Street
- Wasserman, H., 1944
  Plumbing and heating. 2718 Mermaid Avenue
- Waters, E., 1887
  Veterinary surgeon. 281 Raymond Street
- Waters, E.W., 1884, 1888
  Mason and builder. 281, 289 Carroll Street
- Watson, G.E., 1899
  Horseshoer. 441 Madison Street
- Watson & Pittinger, 1898, 1900
  Lumber dealer. Carroll St., on Gowanus Canal
- Watson, T.B., 1873
  Plasterer. 196 Pacific Street
- Watson, Thomas (& Son), 1869, 1879
  Painter. 9, 10, 28 Court Street
- Watson, William W., 1884
  Painter. 88 Livingston Street
- Way, Orland E., 1899-1900
  Carpenter and builder. 2203 Church Avenue
- Weaver, L.H., 1909
  Carpenter and builder. 2722 Atlantic Avenue
- Weber & Quinn, 1880
- Webster, E.G. & Bro. / Webster Bros. & Co., 1877, 1884
  Electroplated ware. 241 & 243 Fulton Street
- Webster, M. (& Son) / M. Webster's Son, 1874, 1876, 1890
  Painter and decorator. 359 Clinton Street, cor. Degraw
- Webster & Redhead, 1886
  Real estate and insurance. 1769 Fulton Street
- Wechsler and Abraham / S. Wechsler & Bro, 1877, 1878, 1880, 1882, 1886, 1889
  Retailers, dry goods. 293 to 299 Fulton St. and 266 & 268 Washington St.
- Weed, 1900
  Caterer. Bedford Ave and Hancock Street
- Weed, W.S. Ice Cream Co., 1907
  Ice cream and catering. 1199-1201 Atlantic Avenue
- Weekes, E.A., Agt., 1872
  Coal and wood dealer. Cor. of Atlantic and Pennsylvania Aves., East New York
- Wege, John, 1886
  Painter. 250 Floyd Street
- Weiderman, George, 1895, 1897
  Electrical contractor. 307 Flatbush Avenue
- Weidner, F. & Co., 1890, 1896, 1900
  Printers and publishers. 105 Meserole Steet, near Ewen
- Weinberg, Jack, 1944-1945
  Tobacconist. 2002 Surf Avenue, cor. 20th Street
- Weir, James (& Sons), 1867, 1868, 1870, 1881, 1891, 1910
  Florist. Successor to Geo. Ingram. 24th and 25th Sts., near 5th; 270 Fulton St. opp. Tillary, and 5 Clinton St.
- Weisenborn, H., 1898
  Metal worker. 318 Court Street
- Weisenborn, J., 1887, 1888, 1890
  Metal worker. 318 Court St. bet. Degraw and Sackett
- Weisenborn, John, 1878
  Locksmith and bellhanger. 402 Bergen St. bet. 5th and Flatbush Aves.
- Weisenborn, M., 1879
  Locksmith and bellhanger. 331 Court St., near Sackett
- Weiss, G., 1915
  Soap makers. Cherry St. and Gardner Ave.
- Welden, John, 1894
  Truckman, rigger and stevedore. West 9th St., near Vernon Avenue
- Weller, L., 1878
  Plumber. 340 Franklin Ave., near Green Avenue
- Welz & Zerweck, 1914, 1919
  Brewers. Cor. Myrtle and Wyckoff Aves.
- Wemstedt, J.P., 1882
  Painters. 67-1/2 6th Avenue
- Wenstrom, John, 1881
  Locksmith and machinist. 179 Flatbush Ave.
- Wenz-Ludy Equipment Co., The, 1912
  Automobile supplies. 1225 Bedford Avenue
- Werbeck, P.A., 1910
  Paper box maker. 1296 Willoughby Avenue
- Werner, G., 1904
  Butcher. Cor. Liberty Ave., and Hemlock Street
- Wernert, John, 1872
  Furniture maker. Atlantic Avenue, bet. Butler and Wyckoff Aves.
- West Baptist Church, Inc.
  Church. 422 Gates Avenue
- West, E., 1884
  Furs and strawgoods. 69 4th Street
- West End Dry Dock Co., The, 1904, 1907
  Shipwright. foot of 27th Street
- West Flatbush League, 1932
  Political association. 320 East 4th St.
- West, George S., 1877-1878
  Milinery goods. 304 Fulton St., bet. Pierrepont and Clinton
- West, John W., 1887
  Painter. 475 Union Street
- Western Union Telegraph Company, The, 1898
  Telegram company. 1719 Fulton Street
- Westlake, R.M., 1876
  Carpenter and builder. 76 Union Avenue; 240 North 2nd Street
- Wheeler, E.E., 1899
  Stables. Cor. S. 8th and Berry Streets
- Wheeler, Geo. E., 1871
  Flour, grains, and horse feed. 105, 111 Gold Street
- Wheeler & Wilson Mfg. Co., 1901
  Manufacturers and dealers of sewing supplies. 579 Fulton Street
- Whelan, E. & J., 1880, 1882
  Carpenters and builders. 62 Schermerhorn St. bet Court and Boerum
- Whipple, R. & Son, 1872
  Carpenters and builders. 266 Court Street
- White, Alex M., 1872
  Real estate [?].
- White Bros., 1897
  Plasterers. 212 41st Street
- White, Charles H., 1892
  Plumber. 124 S. 8th Street
- White, James, 1890-1891
  Roofer. 446 Adelphi Street, near Fulton Avenue
- White, John, 1899
  Horseshoer and blacksmith. 85 Grand Avenue
- White, Marsh & Co., 1889
  Grains and feed dealer. Foot Quay Street
- White, Potter & Paige Mfg. Co., 1886
  Mirror and frame maker. 415 Willoughby Avenue
- White & Price, 1886
  Engineers and machinists. Smith Street, near Hamilton Avenue Bridge
- Whitehorne & Dod, 1873
  Steam fitting works. 101 Franklin Street (old 133)
- Whitehouse, J. & Co., 1877
  Plumber and gas fitter. 43 Ormond Place
- Whitehouse, J.O., 1803
  Shoe dealer. 281 and 283 Fulton Street, bet. Tillary and Johnson
- Whitehouse, J.T., 1860, 1862, 1867
  Shoe dealer. 123 Atlantic Street; 176 & 178 Atlantic Street, opp. the Athenaeum
- Whitehouse Shoe Co., 1887
  Shoe dealer. 265 & 267 Fulton Street
- Whitehouse & Waite, 1867-1868
  Shoe dealer. 281 & 283 Fulton Street, near Tillary
- White Metal Rolling & Stamping Corp., 1936
  Metal work. Moultrie and Calyer Sts.
- White's Express Company, 1902
  Carting. Pakr Ave. & Raymond St. and 448 Madison St.
- Whiting, R.M. Jr., 1868
  Stationery and printing. 379 Fulton St., opp. City Hall
- Whiting, S.F., 1862, 1867
  Clothing dealer. 172 & 174 Fulton St., cor. of Orange St.; 243 Fulton Street, St. Ann's Building
- Whitley, J.H., 1879-1898
  Stoves and furnaces. 193 Fulton St., near Nassau
- Whitney, W.F. Chair Co., 1897
  Chair maker. 495-499 Kent Avenue
- Whittingham, John & Son, 1880, 1882, 1883, 1885
  Vault and lock maker. 81 3rd Street; 55 5th Street
- Wichert & Gardiner, 1920
  Shoe maker. Cor. Schenectady and Atlantic Aves.
- Wider, J. & Co., 1861
  Lace and embroideries. 191 Fulton and 162 Atlantic Sts.
- Wiebusch, Louis, 1873
  Grocer. 78 Fulton Street
- Wieteler, B.H., 1868
  Window shades maker. 105 Myrtle Avenue
- Wilcox, J.G., 1870
  Coal and wood dealer. 47 Sackett Street
- Wilde, G.J., 1882, 1888
  Hardware and guns dealer. 194 York Street, near Gold
- Wildner, Edward, 1890
  House furnishings. 1090 Bedford Avenue
- Wilensky, S., 1943-1944
  Hardware dealer. 2126 Mermaid Avenue
- Wilkes, Daniel W., 1899
  Coal and wood dealer. Fulton, Chauncey Sts. And Lewis Avenue
- Wilkey, Alfred, 1867
  Carriage maker. 262-266 Livingston Street cor. of Hoyt
- Wilkeyson, W.H., 1865
  Painter. 166 South 6th St., bet. 7th and 8th
- Willard, C.A., 1879
  Coal and wood dealer. Third Avenue, cor. 25th Street
- Willes, Thomas, 1877, 1880
  Silk picture maker. 187, 191 Columbia Street, cor. Degraw
- Williams, G.F.F., 1883
  Plumber and gas fitter. 198 Joralemon St., near Court St.
- Williams, George, 1881, 1886
  Plumber and gas fitter. 917, 921 Fulton St., near Clinton Avenue
- Williams, Isaac H., 1872-1873
  Painter. 70 Broadway
- Williams, J.H. & Co., 1898, 1916
  Tool maker. 9-31 Richards St. and 8-26 Bowne St.
- Williams, John S. (& Co.), 1867-1868
  Stoves and heaters dealer. 35 Hicks St., near Middagh
- Williams, M.E., 1894
  Butcher. Erasmus St., cor. Rogers Ave.
- Williams, Thomas, 1874, 1878, 1880
  Paint and varnish dealer. 293, 312 Court Street
- Williams, W.E., 1887
  Plumber. 770 Fulton St.
- Williams, White & Co., 1880
  Hardware maker. Factory, cor. Flushing & Nostrand Aves.; Warehouse, 55 Warren St.
- Williamsburgh City Fire Insurance Company, 1863, 1876
  Broadway and 1st St. and 20 Court St.
- Williamsburgh Coal Yard, 1884
  Coal dealer. Foot of Grand St.
- Williamsburgh Flint Glass Co., 1899-1900
  Glassware. 260 Boerum St.
- Williamsburgh Savings Bank, 1868
- Williamsburgh Yacht Club, 1897
  Yacht club. Seitz's Brooklyn City Park, Flushing Bay
- Williamson Brothers, 1903
  Men's neck wear. 71 Broadway
- Williamson & Gray, 1877
  Carpenters and builders. 91 Hanson Place
- Williamson, James, 1886
  Carpenter and builder. 657 Gates Avenue
- Williamson & Reynolds, 1904
- Williamson's Brooklyn & New York Express Co., 1900
  Freight express. 61 Henry Street
- Willis, J.D., 1866
  Corner Court and Schermerhorn Sts.
- Willis, N., 1891
  Painting and decorating. 355 Graham Avenue
- Willis, T.B. & Bro., 1885
  Hardware. Corner of Court and Schermerhorn Sts.
- Willits, C.D., 1879
  Coal and wood dealer. 644 Fulton Street
- Wilson, A.D., 1867
  Grocer. 184 Grand Street
- Wilson Brothers, 1911
  Greengrocers. 50 Snediker Avenue East New York
- Wilson & Co., 1872
  Furnitire warehouse. 40 & 42 Myrtle Avenue
- Wilson, F.H., 1898
  Postmaster.
- Wilson, George W., 1918
  Watchmaker and optician. 1094 Flatbush Avenue
- Wilson, J., 1873
  Plumber. 16 Wythe Avenue
- Wilson, John, 1863
  Architect and builder. Fulton Ave., near Oxford St.
- Wilson, John, 1880
  Headstones and tomb maker. 195 & 197 24th Street, bet. 4th and 5th Aves.
- Wilson, M., 1876, 1879, 1883
  Milliner. 140 Atlantic Street
- Wilson, W.J., 1885
  Architect and builder. 1645 Fulton St.
- Wilson & Williams, 1876
  Plumber. 284 Broadway
- Winslow, John, 1891
  Shipwright. 282 Carroll St.
- Winston Construction Corporation, 1935
  Builders. 26 Court Street
- Winter, H.M., 1874, 1877, 1878, 1880, 1881
  Milliner. 489 Fulton St.
- Wisbauer, Geo. & Co., 1890
  Paints and brushes dealer. 140 Graham Ave. bet. Boerum St. and Johnson Ave.
- Wischmann, Wm. J., 1917
  Chewing gum maker. 98-100 Grand Avenue
- Wissel, Andrew, 1860
  Night scavenger. 27 Hopkins St., bet. Nostrand and Marcy Aves.
- Wissel, Conrad's Son, 1888
  Scavenger. 50 Court St., near Joralemon St.
- Wissemann Bros., 1916, 1918
  Bakers' supplies. 1035-1149 Wallabout Market
- WNYE, 1940
  Radio station [?]. Brooklyn Technical High School, 29 Fort Greene Place
- Wohl, Louis, 1940
  Plumber. 1808 Avenue R
- Wolf & Lustig, 1897
  House furnishings dealer. 527 5th Ave. bet. 13th and 14th
- Wolf, M., 1869
  Tinsmith and metal roofer. 283 Grand Street
- Wood, E.W., 1862
  Stoves and metal work. 370 Myrtle Avenue, bet. Carlton Ave. and Cumberland St.
- Wood, Geo. & Son, 1889
  Plumbers. 247 Myrtle Avenue & 320 Bridge St.
- Wood, John B., 1880
  Wharfage. Corner of Hamilton Ave. and Gowanus Canal
- Wood, Smith, 1864
  Plumber. 190 Fulton Avenue, near Flatbush Ave.
- Wood, William & Son, 1890
  Plumbers. 190 Sackett St., near Henry St.
- Woodruff, F. & McLean, 1879, 1881
  Ships' supplies. Merchant's stores, foot of Van Dyck St. Red Hook. Woodruff stores, foot Joralemon St.; McLean's Wall St. stores, bet. Fulton and Wall St. ferries
- Woods, Edward, 1898
  Plumber and gas fitter. 38 Myrtle Avenue
- Woods, John R., 1883
  Painter and decorator. 270 Navy Street
- Woodward, Henry M., 1853
  Grocer. 270 Washington Street
- Woolsey, S.W. (& Son), 1887, 1892
  Carpet dealer. 167, 193 Grand St. thru 174 N. 1st St.
- Woolworth, F.W. Co., 1944
  Discount store. Mermaid Ave. & W. 22nd St.
- Worn, Martin, 1879
  161-165 McKibben St.
- Worthington, Henry R., 1896
  Hydrolic works. Van Brunt and Rapelyea Sts.
- Wright & Brook, 1867, 1872, 1881
  Carpenters and builders. 104 and 106 S. Oxford St., near Fulton Avenue
- Wright, George F., 1869, 1878
  Plaster decorations. Cor. Portland and Myrtle Aves; 413 DeKalb Ave., bet. Schenck & Classon Ave.
- Wright, Robert A., 1904
  Realty broker. 254 Tompkins Avenue
- Wright's Hardware, 1936
  Hardware. 2126 Flatbush Avenue
- Wright, Wm., M.D., 1862
  Doctor. 86 4th St.
- Wulff, Chr. F., 1892
  Florist and gardener. Vernon Ave., near the cemetery of the Holy Cross
- Wulpern, C., 1890
  Grocer. 86 Park Ave., SE cor. N. Portland Ave.
- Wust, A.G., 1870
  Attorney. 66 Court Street, rooms 8 & 9
- Wyckoff Brothers, 1884
  Real estate and insruance/coal and wood. 132 Flatbush Avenue, Brighton Square; 1175 Fulton St., west of Bedford
- Wyckoff Heights Hospital Society, 1946
  142 St. Nicholas Avenue
- Wyckoff & Little, 1866, 1870
  Auctioneers, real estate and insurance. 151 Montague Street near Court
- Wynne, P.J., 1869
  Butcher. 39 Carroll Street, near Columbia
- Wynne, Thomas, 1877, 1879
  Butcher. 451 Court Street, near 4th Place or 14 Fourth Place
- Yellow Pine Co., 1909
  Lumber dealer. Yard and mill, Dupont and Franklin Sts.
- Yeshiva of Brighton Beach & Vicinity, 1945
  Religious organization. 2842 Ocean Parkway
- Yeshiva Sharei Zedek Org.
  Religious organization. 2876 West 23rd Street
- Young Friends Lodge, 1932
  Social organization. 361 Stone Avenue
- Young Israel of Prospect Park, 1960
  Religious organization. 74 Linden Boulevard
- Young, J.S., 1914
  Plumber. 229 Hasley Street
- Young Ladies' School, 1867
  129 Clinton Street
- Young Men's Christian Association [Y.M.C.A.], 1930, 1959
  Central Branch, Brooklyn and Queens, 55 Hanson Place; Eastern District Branch, Brooklyn and Queens, Marcy Ave. and S. 9th St.; Central Branch. 11 Bond Street; Of Greater New York, 1121 Bedford Ave.
- Young, Robert, 1897
  Plumber. 249 Nostrand Avenue, near Lafayette Ave.
- Young & Smylie, 1902